

Akshat Gupta

Technical Manager

My journey includes exploring the world of tech from a technical, marketing and managerial perspective. With over 3 years of industry experience in Software Development, I have led and managed teams consisting of more than 30 people globally. A well-rounded business mindset with a technical touch helps me make reasonable decisions and stand out amongst my peers.

akshatvg23@gmail.com

Chennai, India

n linkedin.com/in/akshatvg

github.com/akshatvg

M akshatvg.medium.com

+91 8799979997

www.akshatvg.com

twitter.com/akshatvg

stackoverflow.com/users/11494538/akshat-gupta

instagram.com/akshatvg

EDUCATION

University

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

06/2018 - Present

Information Technology

High School

Chinmaya Vidyalaya, Taylors Road

06/2004 - 06/2018

PCMC

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development Cloud Computing

Digital Marketing Management WordPress

MANAGERIAL SKILLS

Public Speaking Leadership Teamwork

SEO/SEM

Operations

Finance Management Adaptability Strategising

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations and Project Manager

LegalForce RAPC Worldwide

07/2021 - Present

Tasks:

Working as an all-rounded manager for two ventures under the firm- Trademarkia and Nearcast, I was able to balance both corporate and startup work-styles as Trademarkia is an established company running from more than 12 years whereas Nearcast is a startup we had to bring up from scratch.

I helped them create their own in-house engineering teams as the tech team was outsourced before. This included understanding business logic, the tech stack used and hire a team to maintain legacy code and relaying the same to new developers who parallelly revamped the applications into modern tech stacks.

I also helped set up the engineering office in Chennai and handled the finances and operations for the Indian entity.

Setting deadlines, tracking progress, motivating developers & designers, striving towards a product-market fit and coordinating with VCs and Advisors is something I did on a daily basis.

Whenever there was a deadline, I did not hesitate to contribute to the Flutter app and React web teams. I ensured code quality was upto production standards.

Contact: Raj Abhyanker - +1 (408) 398-3126

Developer Evangelist Intern

<u>Agora</u>

07/2020 - 11/2021

Tasks:

I started my journey with Agora by winning a hackathon sponsored by Agora. I started exploring the Agora SDKs and joined the Superstars program. I continued as a member of the program for over a year and mastered the Web SDKs for both RTC and RTM. I was then promoted to the role of a Developer Evangelist Intern in January 2021 under the DevRel team.

In this journey, I was able to help thousands of developers by making Open-Source projects demo-ing how the Web SDK works and how the most daunting tasks could be solved with few lines of code.

Along with a colleague, I conducted workshops teaching Web Development in universities like Columbia, Penn State, NYU, Harvard, UCSC and CalTech, helping participants learn how they could make a functional video calling websites.

I managed the web support channels on Slack as well as Stack Overflow to ensure developers could utilise the fullest potential of the Agora SDKs.

Lastly, I also wrote technical blogs to serve as guides for priority features and examples which would be helpful to developers.

Contact: William Du - +1 (443) 345-6242

PROJECTS

Translated Transcription Service (10/2021)

 Web application to create translated transcribed text to and from any language during video calls using the Agora Web SDKs.

Common Entry Test (12/2020 - 01/2021)

- One stop solution to make club and chapter recruitments in VIT simpler and hassle free.
- This project was used by over 17 clubs, teams and chapters in 2020 with over 70,000 page views and 3,000+ unique users.

Digital Beti (02/2020 - 12/2020)

 Web portal for DigitalBeti, a joint initiative by Facebook and the Government of India to overcome the digital gender gap in India by training women from rural areas to become entrepreneurs, using digital tools.

Josh Skills (06/2020 - 07/2020)

• Mobile first website for Josh Skills with an aim to improve the brand's SEO & online presence for their online courses.

ACHIEVEMENTS

First Place (Profitech 2021) (08/2021)

Won the First Place in the Technology Track out of 240 registered global users.

Second Place (DEVSPACE 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Place in the Industrial Collaborations by Dyte track out of 1,414 registered users.

Third Place (WomenTechies 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Runner Up award in this women-centric hackathon out of around 380 registered users.

First Place (VIT Hack 2020) (10/2020)

Won the first place in the Gravitas AI Case partner problem statement as well as the AWS Educate open challenge out of over 1,200 registered participants.

Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award (09/2020)

Awarded the Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award for exemplary performance at various National & International events and in recognition of my academic performance.

Audience's Favourite (RTE Hack 2020) (09/2020)

Won the Audience's Favourite Award by being the top voted and most liked project of the hackathon.

Best Healthcare Hack (Hophacks Fall 2019) (09/2019)

Won the best Healthcare Hack award powered by Siemens Healthineers out of 44 submitted projects.

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud Platform Business Professional Accreditation (11/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 63280081

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (05/2019 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: LGT29UQ8TT8L

Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 7GRE2XB43TCG

Elastic Google Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: WSEU3OHHJPCW

Reliable Google Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 4G3PTX7RJVCS

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing (07/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

Google Analytics for Beginners

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Advanced Google Analytics

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Google Analytics for Power Users

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Getting Started With Google Analytics 360

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Introduction to Data Studio

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Google Tag Manager Fundamentals

(01/2021 - 01/2024)

Python (Basic) (09/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: B7D22892D983